WindWhistling
Birds Chirping
The hills arealive
With thesound ofmusic
With songs theyhavesung
Fora thousandyears
The hills fill myheart
With thesound ofmusic
Myheartwants tosing
Everysong it hears
Myheartwants to beat
Likethewings ofthe birds
That risefrom the lake
Tothetrees
Myheartwants tosigh
Likea chimethatflies
From a church on a breeze
To laugh likea brook
When ittrips and falls
Overstones on itsway
Tosing through the night
Likea larkwho is learning to pray
I
Gotothe hills
When myheart is lonely
I know I will hear
What I've heard before
Myheartwill be blessed
With thesound ofmusic
And I'll sing
Once
More
Church Bells Ring
Oh!
Chorus]
♪♪ Propterea in exaltabitcaput♪♪
Woman] ♪♪ Gloria Patri,
et Filio EtSpiritui Sancto♪♪
Chorus] ♪♪ Sicuterat in
principio Et nunc, etsemper♪♪
♪♪ Et in saecula saeculorum
Amen♪♪
♪♪ Rexadmirabilis
Ettriumphatornobilis♪♪
Dulcedoinefbilis
Inefbilis
♪♪Totus desiderabilis
Totus desiderabilis♪♪
Church Bells Ring
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia
Alleluia, alleluia
Reverend Mother.
Sister Bernice.
I simplycannotfind her.
Maria?
She's missing from
theabbeyagain.
Perhapsweshould
have puta cowbell around herneck.
Haveyou tried the barn?
You know how much
sheadores theanimals.
I have looked everywhere,
in all ofthe usual places.
Sister Bernice,
considering that it's Maria...
I suggestyou look
in someplace unusual.
Well, Reverend Mother...
I hopethis new infraction...
endswhateverdoubts
you maystill have...
about Maria's future here.
I always tryto keepfaith
in mydoubts, Sister Berthe.
Afterall, thewool ofa blacksheep
isjustaswarm.
Weare nottalking aboutsheep...
blackorwhite,
Sister Margaretta.
Ofall thecandidates
forthe novitiate...
I would say Maria is
the least likely--
Children, children!
Wewerespeculating
aboutthequalifications...
ofsomeofourpostulants.
The mistress ofnovices...
and the mistress ofpostulants...
weretrying to help me...
byexpressing
opposite points ofview.
Tell me, SisterCatherine,
whatdoyou thinkofMaria?
She's awonderful girl,
someofthetime.
SisterAgatha?
It'sveryeasyto like Maria...
exceptwhen it's difficult.
Andyou, SisterSophia?
I love herverydearly...
butshealways seems to be
in trouble, doesn'tshe?
Exactlywhat I say.
Sheclimbs a tree
and scrapes herknee
Herdress has gota tear
Shewaltzes
on herwayto Mass
Andwhistles on thestair
And underneath herwimple
She has curlers in herhair
I'veeven heard hersinging
In theabbey
She's always lateforchapel
But herpenitence is real
She's always late
foreverything
Exceptforeverymeal
I hateto havetosayit
But I veryfirmlyfeel
Maria's notan asset
totheabbey
I'd liketosayaword
in herbehalf
Then sayit, Sister Margaretta.
Maria
Makes me laugh
Howdoyou solve
a problem like Maria?
Howdoyou catch a cloud
and pin itdown?
Howdoyou find aword
that means Maria?
Aflibbertigibbet
Awill-o'-the-wisp
Aclown
Manya thingyou know
you'd liketotell her
Manya thing
sheoughtto understand
But howdoyou
make herstay
And listen toallyou say?
Howdoyou keep
awave upon thesand?
Oh, howdoyou solve
a problem like Maria?
Howdoyou hold a moonbeam
Inyourhand?
When I'm with her, I'm confused
Outoffocus, and bemused
And I neverknow
exactlywhere I am
Unpredictableasweather
She's as flightyas a feather
She's a darling
She's a demon
She's a lamb
She'd out-pesteranypest
Drivea hornetfrom its nest
Shecan throwawhirling
dervish outofwhirl
She is gentle, She iswild
She's a riddle, She's a child
She's a headache
She's an angel
She's a girl
Howdoyou solvea problem
like Maria?
Howdoyou catch a cloud
and pin itdown?
Howdoyou find
aword that means Maria?
Aflibbertigibbet
Awill-o'-the-wisp
Aclown
Manya thingyou know
you'd liketotell her
Manya thing
sheoughtto understand
But howdoyou make herstay
And listen toallyou say?
Howdoyou keep
awave upon thesand?
Oh, howdoyou solve
a problem like Maria?
DoorSlams
Howdoyou hold a moonbeam
In
Your
Hand?
You maygo in now, Maria.
Come here, mychild.
Now, sitdown.
Oh. Oh, Reverend Mother,
I'm sosorry.
Ijustcouldn't help myself.
Thegateswereopen...
and the hillswere beckoning,
and before I--
Dear, I haven'tsummoned
you hereforapologies.
Oh, please, Mother, do let me
askforforgiveness.
Ifitwould makeyou feel better.
Yes.Well,you see,
theskywas so bluetoday...
and everythingwas
sogreen and fragrant.
Ijust had to bea partofit.
And the bird kept leading me
higherand higher...
as though itwanted metogo right
through thecloudswith it.
Child, supposedarkness
had comeandyouwere lost?
Oh, Mother, I could never
be lost upthere.
That's mymountain.
I was brought upon it.
Itwas the mountain
that led metoyou.
Oh?
When I was a child,
I would comedown the mountain...
and climba treeand look
overintoyourgarden.
I'd seethesisters atwork...
and I'd hearthem sing
on theirwaytovespers...
which brings metoanother
transgression, Reverend Mother.
I was singing outtheretoday
without permission.
Maria, it is onlyhere
in theabbey...
thatwe have rules about
postulants singing.
I can'tseem tostop
singingwhereverl am.
Andwhat'sworse, I can't
seem tostopsaying things--
Everything and anything
I thinkand feel.
Some peoplewould
call that honesty.
But it's terrible,
Reverend Mother.
You know howSister Berthe
always makes me kiss thefloor...
afterwe'vehadadisagreement?
Latelyl'vetaken to kissing
thefloorwhen I see hercoming...
justtosavetime.
Maria,whenyou saw us
overtheabbeywall...
and longed to beoneofus...
thatdidn't necessarilymean...
thatyouwere prepared for
thewaywe live here, did it?
No, Mother,
but I pray, and I try...
and I am learning.
I reallyam.
What is the most important lesson
you have learned here, mychild?
Tofind outwhat
is thewill ofGod...
and todo it
wholeheartedly.
Maria...
itseems to be
thewill ofGod...
thatyou leave us.
- Leaveyou?
- Onlyforawhile, Maria.
Oh, no, please, don'tdothat.
Don'tsend meaway.
This iswhere I belong.
It's myhome, myfamily.
It's mylife.
Butareyou truly
readyforit?
Yes, I am.
Perhaps ifyou go
out intotheworld...
fora time...
knowingwhatwe
expectofyou...
youwill have
a chancetofind out...
ifyou could expect it
ofyourself.
I knowwhatyou expect,
Mother, and I can do it.
- I promise I can.
- Maria.
Yes, Mother...
ifit is God'swill.
There is a family
nearSalzburg...
that needs a governess
until September.
September?
Totakecare
ofseven children.
Seven children!
Doyou likechildren, Maria?
Well,yes, butseven!
I will tell CaptainVonTrapp...
toexpectyou tomorrow.
Uh, Captain?
A retired officerof
the Imperial Navy.
Afine man
and a braveone.
His wifedied
severalyearsago:.
Leaving'himalone
withthechildren.
I understand he's had
a mostdifficulttime...
managing to keep
a governess there.
Uh,whydifficult,
Reverend Mother?
The Lordwill showyou
in his own good time.
Chorus] ♪♪ Dulcedo
ineffabilis Totus desiderabilis♪♪
♪♪Totus desiderabilis♪♪
When the Lord closes a door...
somewhere heopens awindow.
Whatwill this daybe like?
I wonder
Whatwill myfuture be?
Itcould besoexciting
To beout in theworld
To befree
Myheartshould
bewildlyrejoicing
Oh,what's the matterwith me?
I havealways
longed foradventure
Todothethings
I've neverdared
Now here I'm facing adventure
Thenwhy
Am I soscared?
Acaptainwith 7 children
What's sofearsomeaboutthat?
Oh, I muststopthesedoubts,
All theseworries
Ifl don't, Ijust know
I'll turn back
I mustdream
ofthethings I am seeking
I am seeking thecourage
I lack
Thecourageto
servethem with reliance
Face mymistakes
withoutdefiance
Showthem I'm worthy
Andwhile I showthem
I'll
Show
Me
So
Letthem bring on
all theirproblems
I'll do betterthan mybest
I haveconfidence
They'll put metothetest
But I'll makethem see
I haveconfidence in me
Somehow I will impress them
I will befirm but kind
And all thosechildren
Heaven bless them
Theywill lookupto me
and mind me
With each step,
I am morecertain
Everythingwill turn outfine
I haveconfidence
theworld can all be mine
They'll havetoagree
I haveconfidence in me
I haveconfidence in sunshine
I haveconfidence in rain
I haveconfidencethat
springwill comeagain
Besideswhich,you see
I haveconfidence in me
Strength doesn't
lie in numbers
lie inwealth
Strength lies in nights
ofpeaceful slumbers
Whenyouwake up,Wake up
It's healthy, all I trust
I leave myheartto
All I trust becomes myown
I haveconfidence in confidence
Alone...
Oh, help.
I haveconfidence
In confidencealone
Besideswhich,you see
I haveconfidence
In me
Doorbell Rings
Oh!
Hello! Here I am.
I'm from theconvent.
I'm the newgoverness, Captain.
And I'm theold butler, Fraulein.
Oh.Well, howdoyou do?
Hmm.
You'll, uh,wait here, please.
DoorOpens
In thefuture,
you'll kindlyremember...
therearecertain rooms
in this house...
which are not
to bedisturbed.
Yes, Captain, sir.
Andwhydoyou stare
at methatway?
You don't lookatall
likea sea captain, sir.
I'm afraidyou don't look
verymuch likea governess.
- Turnaround,please.
- What?
Turn.
Hatoff.
It's thedress.You'll have
to puton anotherone...
beforeyou meetthechildren.
But I don't haveanotherone.
Whenweentered theabbey...
ourworldlyclothes
weregiven tothe poor.
Whataboutthis one?
The poordidn'twantthis one.
Hmm.
I would have made
myselfa newdress...
buttherewasn'ttime.
I can make myown clothes.
Well, I'll seethatyou
getsome material.
Today, ifpossible.
Now, Fraulein...
Maria.
Fraulein Maria,
I don't know how much...
the motherabbess
has toldyou.
Not much.
You'rethe 1 2th in
a long lineofgovernesses...
who havecometo look
aftermychildren...
sincetheirmotherdied.
I trustthatyouwill bean
improvementon the lastone.
Shestayed only2 hours.
What'swrong
with thechildren, sir?
There's nothingwrong
with thechildren...
onlythegovernesses.
Theywerecompletelyunable
to maintain discipline.
Without it, this house
cannot be properlyrun.
Willyou please
rememberthat, Fraulein?
Yes, sir.
Everymorningyouwill drill
thechildren in theirstudies.
I will not permitthem todream
awaytheirsummerholidays.
Each afternoon theywill
march aboutthegrounds...
breathing deeply.
Bedtime is to bestrictly
observed, noexceptions.
Excuse me, sir,
when dotheyplay?
Youwill seeto itthat
theyconductthemselves...
atall timewith the utmost
orderliness and decorum.
I'm placingyou in command.
Yes, sir!
Whistle Blows
Running Footsteps
BlowingWhistle
Now, this isyournew
governess, Fraulein Maria.
As I soundyoursignals...
youwill stepforward
and giveyourname.
You, Fraulein,
will listen carefully.
Learn thosesignals soyou can
call them whenyouwantthem.
BlowingWhistle
Liesl.
Friedrich.
Louisa.
Kurt.
Brigitta.
Marta.
BlowsWhistle
And Gretl.Ahem.
Now, let's see
howwellyou listened.
Oh, I won't need towhistle
forthem, Reverend Captain.
I mean, I'll usetheirnames.
And such lovelynames.
VonTrapp: Fraulein,
this is a large house.
Thegrounds areveryextensive
and I will not haveanyoneshouting.
Takethis, please.
Learn to use it.
Thechildrenwill helpyou.
Now,when I wantyou,
this iswhatyouwill hear.
Whistle Blows
No, sir. I'm sorry, sir.
I could neveranswer
toawhistle.
Whistles arefordogs
and cats and otheranimals...
but notforchildren,
and definitelynotforme.
Itwould betoo humiliating.
Fraulein,wereyou this
much troubleattheabbey?
Oh, much more, sir.
Hmm.
Whistle Blows
Excuse me, sir.
I don't knowyoursignal.
You maycall meCaptain.
Atease.
Well, nowthat
there'sjust us...
wouldyou pleasetell me
allyournames again...
and howoldyou are?
I'm Liesl.
I'm 1 6years old...
and I don't need a governess.
I'm gladyou told me, Liesl.
We'lljust begood friends.
I'm Friedrich.
I'm 1 4. I'm impossible.
Really?Whotoldyou
that, Friedrich?
FrauleinJosephine,
4 governesses ago.
I'm Brigitta.
You, um, didn'ttell me
howoldyou are, Louisa.
I'm Brigitta.
She's Louisa.
She's 13years old...
andyou'resmart.
I'm 1 0, and I thinkyourdress...
is the ugliestone I eversaw.
Brigitta,you shouldn'tsaythat.
Whynot? Don'tyou thinkit's ugly?
Ofcourse,
but Fraulein Hilda'swas ugliest.
I'm Kurt. I'm 11.
I'm incorrigible.
Congratulations.
What's incorrigible?
I thinkit means...
youwantto be
treated likea boy.
Mm-hmm?
I'm Marta...
and I'm gonna be7
onTuesday.
And I'd likea pinkparasol.
Well, pink's myfavoritecolor, too.
StompStomp
Yes,you'reGretl...
andyou're 5years old?
My,you're practicallya lady.
Now I have
totellyou a secret--
I've neverbeen
a governess before.
You meanyou don't knowanything
about being a governess?
Nothing. I'll need
lots ofadvice.
Well, the bestway
tostart is to besure...
totell Fatherto mind
his own business.
You must nevercome
todinneron time.
Nevereatsoupquietly.
Slurp
And during dessert
always blowyournose.
Don'tyou believeaword
theysay, Fraulein.
Whynot?
- Because I likeyou!
- Clapping']
All right, children,
outsideforyourwalk.
Father's orders.
Now, hurryup, hurryup.
Quick, quick, quick!
Fraulein Maria...
I'm Frau Schmidt,
the housekeeper.
- Howdoyou do?
I'll showyou toyourroom.
Follow me.
Poorlittledears.
Ah!Aah!Aah! Oh!
- Oh--
- You'reverylucky.
With Fraulein Helga,
itwas a snake.
Good evening.
Good evening, children.
Good evening,
Fraulein Maria.
Aah!
Enchanting little ritual.
Somethingyou learned
attheabbey?
No, it's...um...
um...
rheumatism.
Excuse me. Haven'twe
forgotten tothankthe Lord?
Forwhatweare
aboutto receive...
maythe Lord make us
trulythankful.Amen.
Amen.
Children]
I'd liketothankeach ofyou
forthe precious gift...
you left in mypocket
earliertoday.
Um:.whatgift?
It's meantto bea secret
between thechildren and me.
Then I suggestthatyou
keep itand let us eat.
Knowing how nervous
I must have been...
a strangerin a new household...
knowing how important itwas
formetofeel accepted...
itwassokind
andthoughtfulofyou:.
To make myfirst moments here
sowarm, happy, and pleasant.
- What is the matter, Marta?
- Nothing.
ChildrenCrying']
Fraulein, isit
tobeateverymeal:
ormerelyatdinnertime...
thatyou intend leading
us all through this rare...
andwonderful newworld
ofindigestion?
They'reall right.
They'rejust happy.
Crying Gets Louder
Doorbell Rings
Rolfe, good evening.
Good evening, Franz.
I trusteverything
is undercontrol?
Yes.Yes.
Good.
- Arethereanydevelopments?
- Perhaps.
Is thecaptain at home?
He's atdinner.
With thefamily?
Yes.
Pleasegive him this
telegram atonce.
Certainly.
- Telegram foryou, sir.
- Mm.
Franz,whodelivered it?
Thatyoung lad Rolfe, ofcourse.
Father, mayl beexcused?
Hmm.
Children, in the morning,
I shall begoing toVienna.
All
Notagain, Father!
How longwillyou be
gonethis time, Father?
I'm notsure, Gretl.
To visitBaronessSchraederagain?
Mindyourown business!
As a matteroffact,yes, Louisa.
Whycan'tweeverget
toseethe baroness?
Whywouldshe wanttoseeyou?
Itjustso happens, Marta,
you aregoing toseethe baroness.
I'mbringing'herback
withmeto visitusall
Children]
Cood!
And Uncle Max.
- Uncle Max!
Rolfe!
Oh, Rolfe.
No, Liesl,we mustn't.
Whynot, silly?
I don't know--
Isn'tthiswhyyou're
herewaiting forme?
Yes, ofcourse.
I've missedyou, Liesl.
You have? How much?
So much that I even thought
ofsendingyou a telegram...
justso I'd beable
todeliverit here.
Oh, that's a lovelythought.
Whydon'tyou, right now?
But I'm here.
Please, Rolfe,
send mea telegram.
I'll start itforyou.
Dear Liesl...
I'd liketo beabletotellyou
how I feel aboutyou. Stop.
Unfortunately, thiswire
is alreadytooexpensive.
Sincerely, Rolfe.
"Sincerely"?
Cordially.
"Cordially"?
Affectionately?
Mmm!
Will there beanyreply?
Dear Rolfe... stop.
Don'tstop.Your Liesl.
Ifonlywedidn't
always havetowait...
forsomeonetosend
Fathera telegram.
Howdo I knowwhen
I'll seeyou again?
Well, let's see.
I could come here bymistake...
with a telegram
forColonel Schneider.
He's herefrom Berlin,
stayingwith--
Noone's supposed to
know he's here.
Don'ttellyourfather, now.
Whynot?
Well,yourfather's
so...soAustrian.
We'reall Austrian.
Well, some peoplethink
weoughtto beGerman...
and they'reverymad
atthosewhodon'tthinkso.
They'regetting readyto--
Well, let's hopeyourfather
doesn'tget intotrouble.
Don'tworryabout Father.
He's a big naval hero.
Hewas even decorated
bytheemperor.
I know.
I don'tworryabout him...
but I doworry
about his daughter.
Me?Why?
Well,you'reso...
What?
You'resuch a baby!
I'm 1 6.
What's such
a babyaboutthat?
Youwait, littlegirl,
on an emptystage
Forfatetoturn the lighton
Yourlife, littlegirl,
is an emptypage
That menwill wanttowriteon
Towriteon
You are 1 6 going on 17
Baby, it's timetothink
Betterbeware,
Becannyand careful
Baby,you'reon the brink
You are 1 6, going on 17
Fellowswill fall in line
Eageryoung lads
and roués and cads
Will offeryou food andwine
Totallyunprepared areyou
Tofaceaworld ofmen
Timid and shy
and scared areyou
Ofthings beyondyour Ken
You need someone
olderandwiser
Tellingyouwhattodo
I am 17 going on 1 8
I'll takecareofyou
Thunder]
I am 1 6 going on 17
I knowthat I'm naive
Fellows I meet
maytell me I'm sweet
Andwillingly, I believe
I am 1 6 going on 17
Innocentas a rose
Bachelordandies
Drinkers ofbrandies
Whatdo I knowofthose?
Totallyunprepared am I
Tofaceaworld ofmen
Timid and shyand scared am I
Ofthings beyond my Ken
I need someone
olderandwiser
Telling mewhattodo
You are 17 going on 1 8
I'll depend onyou
Wheee!
- KnockCnDoor]
- Come in.
Frau Schmidt.
Foryournewdresses,
Fraulein Maria.
Thecaptain had these
sentoutfrom town.
Oh, how lovely.
I'm surethesewill make...
the prettiestclothes I'veeverhad.
Tell me, doyou thinkthecaptain...
would get mesome more
material ifl asked him?
How manydresses
does a governess need?
Notforme.
Forthechildren.
I wantto makethem
some playclothes.
TheVonTrappchildren don't play.
Theymarch.
Surely,you don'tapproveofthat.
Eversincethecaptain
lost his poorwife...
he runs this house...
as ifhewereon one
ofhis ships again.
Whistles, orders:.
No more music,
no more laughing.
Nothing that
reminds him ofher.
Even thechildren.
It's sowrong!
Oh,well. Howdo
you likeyourroom?
There'llbenewdrapes
atthe windows.
Newdrapes?
Butthesearefine.
Nevertheless, newones
have been ordered.
Oh, but I really
don't need them.
Good night, now.
Frau Schmidt...
doyou thinkifl asked
thecaptain tomorrow...
aboutthe material...
He's leaving forVienna
in the morning.
Oh,yes, ofcourse.
Well, how longwill he begone?
Thatall depends.
The lasttime
hevisited the baroness...
- hestayed fora month.
- Oh.
I shouldn't besaying this--
Nottoyou, I mean,
I don't knowyou thatwell--
But ifyou askme...
thecaptain's thinking
veryseriously...
ofmarrying thewoman
beforethesummer's over.
Oh, thatwould bewonderful!
Thechildrenwill have
a motheragain.
Yes.Well, good night.
Good night.
Dear Father...
now I knowwhy
you'vesent me here.
To helpthesechildren prepare
themselves fora new mother.
And I praythatthiswill become
a happyfamilyin thysight.
God bless thecaptain.
God bless Liesl and Friedrich.
God bless Louisa, Brigitta,
Marta, and littleGretl.
And, oh, I forgottheotherboy.
What's his name?
Well, God bless
what's-his-name.
God bless the Reverend Mother...
and Sister Margaretta...
and everybody
at NonnbergAbbey.
And now, dearGod,
about Liesl...
help herto know
that I'm herfriend.
And help hertotell me
whatshe's been upto.
Areyou going totell on me?
Shh. Help me
to be understanding...
sothat I mayguide herfootsteps.
In the name
ofthe Father, theSon...
and the HolyGhost, amen.
I was outtaking awalk...
and somebodylocked thedoors
earlierthan usual...
and I didn'twantto
wakeeverybodyup.
Sowhen I saw
yourwindowopen--
You're notgoing to
tell Father, areyou?
How in theworld
didyou climb up here?
It's howwealways
got intothis room...
to playtricks on thegoverness.
Louisacanmakeit:.
With awholejarof
spiders in herhand.
Spiders?
Oh.
Liesl,wereyou out
walking all byyourself?
You know, ifwewash
thatdress outtonight...
nobodywould
notice ittomorrow.
You could putthis on.
Takeyourdress in there.
Put ittosoakin the bathtub.
Then come backhere
and siton the bed...
andwe'll havea talk.
I toldyou today...
I didn't need a governess.
Well, maybe I do.
Thunder]
Gretl?
Areyouscared?
Thunder]
You're notfrightened of
a thunderstorm, areyou?
Youjuststayright here
with me.
Wherearetheothers?
They'reasleep.
They're notscared.
Thunder]
Oh, no? Look.
All right, everybody.
Up hereon the bed.
Really?
Well,justthis once.
Comeon.
All we havetodo is
waitforthe boys.
Youwon'tseethem.
Boys are brave.
Thunder]
You boysweren'tscared,
too,wereyou?
No.Wejustwanted to be
surethatyouweren't.
That'sverythoughtful
ofyou, Friedrich.
Itwasn'tmyidea.
Itwas Kurt's.
Kurt!That's theone
I leftout. God bless Kurt.
Thunder]
Whydoes itdothat?
Well, the lightning...
says something tothethunder...
and thethunderanswers back.
The lightning must be nasty.
Not really.
Thenwhydoes thethunder
getsoangry?
It makes mewanttocry.
Thunder]
When anything bothers me
and I'm feeling unhappy...
Ijusttryand think
ofnicethings.
Children
What kind ofthings?
Oh,well, let mesee.
Nicethings...
Daffodils!
Green Meadows...
skies full ofstars...
raindrops on roses...
andwhiskers on kittens...
Brightcopperkettles
Andwarm woolen mittens
Brown paperpackages
Tied upwith strings
- Thesearea fewofmyfavoritethings
- Thunder]
Cream-colored ponies
And crispapplestrudels
Doorbells and sleigh bells
And schnitzel with noodles
Wild geesethatfly
With the moon on theirwings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
Girls inwhitedresses
With bluesatin sashes
Snowflakes thatstay
On mynoseand eyelashes
Silverwhitewinters
That melt intosprings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
When thedog bites
When the beestings
When I'm feeling sad
I simplyremember
myfavoritethings
And then I don'tfeel
So bad
Does it reallywork?
Ofcourse itdoes.You tryit.
Whatthings doyou like?
Pussywillows.
Christmas!
Bunnyrabbits!
Snakes!
Chocolate icing!
Noschool!
Pillowfights!
Telegrams!
Birthdaypresents!
Anypresents!
Ladybugs!
Agood sneeze!
Ah-Choo
Gesundheit!
Seewhatfun it is?
Raindrops on roses
Andwhiskers on kittens
Brightcopperkettles
Andwarm woolen mittens
Brown paperpackages
Tied upwith strings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
Cream-colored ponies
And crispapplestrudels
Doorbells and sleigh bells
And schnitzel with noodles
Wild geesethatfly
With the moon
on theirwings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
Oh!Together!
Girls inwhitedresses
With bluesatin sashes
Snowflakes thatstay
On mynoseand eyelashes
Silverwhitewinters
That melt intosprings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
When thedog bites--
Singing StopsAbruptly
Hello.
Fraulein, did I nottellyou...
that bedtime is to bestrictly
observed in this household?
Thechildrenwere
upset bythestorm.
I thought--
You did, sir.
And doyou ordoyou not
havedifficulty...
remembering such
simple instructions?
Onlyduring
thunderstorms, sir.
Giggles
- Liesl?
- Yes, Father?
I don't recall seeingyou
anywhereafterdinner.
Oh, really?
Well, as a matteroffact--
Yes?
Well, I-- I was--
Whatshewould liketo
sayis thatsheand I...
have been getting better
acquainted tonight.
Butit'stoolatenow
togointoallthat.
Comealong, children,
you heardyourfather.
Go backto bed immediately.
Fraulein,you have
managed to remember...
that I'm leaving
in the morning?
Is italso possible
thatyou remember...
thatthefirst rule
in this house is discipline?
Then I trustthat before I return...
youwill haveacquired some?
Captain.
I wonderif, beforeyou go...
I could talktoyou
aboutsomeclothes...
forthechildren,
forwhen theyplay.
Ifl couldjust have
some material--
You areobviouslymanythings...
notthe leastofwhich
is repetitious.
Butthey'rechildren!
Yes...
and I'm theirfather.
Good night.
DoorSlams]
Oh!
Thunder]
Girls inwhitedresses
With bluesatin sashes
When thedog bites
When the beestings
When I'm feeling sad
I simplyremember
myfavoritethings
And then I don'tfeel
So bad
- ChildrenCiggling']
- Cirl]Whereare wegoing?
Lookoverhere.
Oh, look!
Comeon!
Ho!
Fraulein Maria...
canwedothis everyday?
Don'tyou thinkyou'd soon
gettired ofit, Louisa?
I supposeso.
Everyotherday?
I haven't had so much fun...
sincethedaywe putglueon...
FrauleinJosephine's toothbrush.
I can't understand how
children as niceasyou...
can manageto playsuch
awful tricks on people.
- Oh, it's easy.
- Butwhydo it?
- Howelsecanweget Father's attention?
- Yes.
Oh, I see.
Well,we'll haveto
thinkaboutthatone.
All right, everybody!
Overhere!
Whatarewegoing todo?
Let's thinkofsomething
tosing forthe baroness.
Fatherdoesn't like us tosing.
Well, perhapswecan
change his mind.
Now,whatsongs
doyou know?
Wedon't knowanysongs.
Notany?
Wedon'teven know
howtosing.
Well, let's not loseanytime.
You must learn.
But how?
Let's startattheverybeginning
Averygood placetostart
Whenyou readyou beginwith
A-B-C
Whenyou sing
you beginwith
Do Re Mi
Thefirst3 notes
just happen to be
Do Re Mi
Do Re Mi Fa So LaTi
Oh, let's see ifl can
make iteasier. Mmm...
Doe, a deer
Afemaledeer
Ray, a dropofgolden sun
Me, a name I call myself
Far, a long, longwayto run
Sew, a needle pulling thread
La, a notetofollowsew
Tea, a drinkwithjam and bread
Thatwill bring us backto Do
Oh, oh, oh
Doe
Adeer, a femaledeer
Ray
Adropofgolden sun
Me
A name I call myself
Far
A long, longwayto run
Sew, a needle
pulling thread
La, a notetofollowsew
Tea
Adrinkwithjam and bread
Thatwill bring us backto
Doe, a deer, a femaledeer
Ray, a dropofgolden sun
Me, a name I call myself
Far, a long, longwayto run
Sew, a needle pulling thread
La, a notetofollowsew
Tea, a drink
withjam and bread
Thatwill bring us backto Do
Do Re Mi Fa So LaTi Do
So Do
Now, children,
do re mi fa soand soon...
areonlythetoolswe use
to build a song.
Onceyou havethese notes
inyourheads...
you can sing a million
differenttunes...
bymixing them up.
Likethis--
Uh...
So Do La Fa Mi Do Re
Canyou dothat?
So Do LaTi Do Re Do
Now put itall together.
So Do La Fa Mi Do Re
So Do LaTi Do Re Do
Good!
But itdoesn't
mean anything.
Sowe put inwords,
oneword foreverynote.
Likethis...
Whenyou know
the notes tosing
You can sing mostanything
Together!
Whenyou know
the notes tosing
You can sing mostanything
Doe
Adeer, a femaledeer
Ray
Adropofgolden sun
Me
A name I call myself
Far
A long, longwayto run
Sew
A needle pulling thread
La
A notetofollowsew
Tea
Adrinkwithjam and bread
Thatwill bring us backtodo
Do Re Mi Fa So LaTi
Do Do
Ti La So Fa Mi Re
Do Mi-Mi
Mi So-So
Re Fa-Fa
LaTi-Ti
Do Mi-Mi, Mi So-So
Re Fa-Fa, LaTi-Ti
Whenyou know
the notes tosing
You can sing mostanything
Doe, a deer
Afemaledeer
Ray, a dropofgolden sun
Me, a name I call myself
Far, a long, longwayto run
Sew, a needle pulling thread
La, a notetofollowsew
Tea, a drink
withjam and bread
Thatwill bring us backto
So Do La Fa Mi Do Re
So Do La Fa
Ti La So
Mi Fa
Ti Re
Ti Do
So Do
The mountains are
magnificent, Georg...
reallymagnificent.
I had them put up
justforyou, darling.
Oh.
Laughs
Even ifit's toa height
of1 0,000 feet...
Georg always believes
in rising totheoccasion.
Unless thejokes improve, Max,
I'm taking backmyinvitation.
You didn't invite me
toyourvilla.
I invited myself.
Naturally.
You needed a chaperone...
and I needed a placetostay...
wherethecuisine is superb,
thewinecellarunexcelled...
and the price... perfect.
Max,you areoutrageous!
Notatall.
I'm averycharming sponge.
- Hmm.
- MaleChorus] ♪♪Alleluia, alleluia♪♪
- Listen.
-♪♪Alleluia♪♪
- It'sthemonasterychoir
-♪♪Alleluia, alleluia♪♪
They'regood.
Verygood.
I mustexplorethis territory
in the nextfewdays.
Somewherea hungry
littlesinging group...
iswaiting for Max Detweiler...
to pluckitoutofobscurity...
and make itfamous...
attheSalzburg folkfestival.
Theygetthefame.
You getthe money.
'Tis unfair, I admit it.
Butsomedaythat'll bechanged.
I shall getthefame, too.
Laughs
Laughing'AndScreaming']
Baroness]
Coodheavens, what'sthis?
Oh, it's nothing.
Justsome local urchins.
Sighs This reallyis exciting
forme, Georg...
being herewithyou.
Ho ho ho.
Trees, lakes, mountains...
whenyou'veseen one,
you'veseen them all.
That is notwhat I mean,
andyou know it.
Ah,you mean me.
I'm exciting?
Is thatso impossible?
No,just, uh,
highlyimprobable.
Thereyou go, running
yourselfdown again.
Well, I'm a dangerous driver.
Laughs
You know,you're
much less ofa riddle...
when I seeyou here, Georg.
In mynatural habitat?
Yes, exactly.
Areyou trying tosay
that I'm moreat home here...
among the birds and theflowers...
and thewind that moves
through thetrees...
likea restless sea, hmm?
How poetic.
Yes, itwas, rather,
wasn't it?
Moreat home here
than inVienna...
in allyourglittering salons...
gossiping gaily
with bores I detest...
soaking myselfin champagne...
stumbling aboutto
waltzes byStrauss...
I can'teven remember.
Is thatwhatyou're
trying tosay?
Moreorless,yes.
Now,whatever
gaveyou that idea?
Oh, I do like it here, Georg.
It's so lovelyand peaceful.
Howcanyou leave it
as often asyou do?
Oh, pretending to be
madlyactive, I suppose.
Activitysuggests a life
filledwith purpose.
Could it be running
awayfrom memories?
Mm-hmm.
Orperhapsjustsearching
fora reason tostay.
Oh, I hopethat'swhyyou've
been coming toVienna sooften.
Orwerethereother
distractions there?
Oh, I'd hardlycallyou
a meredistraction, darling.
Well,whatwouldyou
call me, Georg?
Hmm... lovely.
Charming,witty, graceful.
Theperfeecthostess.
And--you'regonna
hatemeforthis--
in away, mysavior.
Oh, how unromantic.
Well, I would be
an ungrateful wretch...
ifl didn'ttellyou at leastonce...
that iswasyou
who broughtsome meaning...
backinto mylife.
Oh, I am amusing, I suppose.
And I do havethefinest
couturierinVienna...
and the mostglittering
circleoffriends.
- And I dogivesome rathergayparties.
- Ho, ho, ho.Yes.
Buttakeall thataway...
andyou havejustwealthy,
unattached little me...
-searchingjust likeyou.
- Chuckles
Morestrudel, Herr Detweiler?
How manyhave I had?
Two.
Make itan uneven three.
Still eating, Max, hmm?
Must be unhappy.
That marvelous mixed quartet...
I've been trying for
months tosteal away...
from Saul Hurok--
What happened, darling?
Yesterday, Sasha Petrie
stolethem first.
Ifthere's onething
I hate, it's a thief.
Max,you reallymusttry
and learn to loveyourself.
Forthis, I had tocall
Paris, Rome, and Stockholm.
On Georg's telephone,
ofcourse?
Well, howelsecould I afford it?
Oh, dear, I like rich people.
I likethewaytheylive.
I liketheway I live
when I'm with them.
I wonder
wherethechildren are.
Obviouslytheymust have
heard I was coming...
andwent into hiding.
I was hoping they'd
be heretowelcomeyou.
Uh, Max, dostepoutof
characterfora moment...
and tryand becharming.
Well?
Well,what?
Haveyou made up
Georg's mindyet?
Do I hearwedding bells?
Pealing madly.
But not necessarilyforme.
What kind oftalk's that?
That is none-of-your-business talk, Max.
I'm terriblyfond ofGeorg...
and I will not haveyou
toyingwith us.
But I'm a child. I liketoys,
sotell meeverything.
Oh, comeon, tell Max
everyteensyweensy...
intimate, disgusting detail.
Well, let'sjustsay
I havea feeling...
I maybe hereon approval.
Well, I approveofthat.
Howcanyou miss?
Fartooeasily.
Ifl knowyou, darling,
and I do,youwill find away.
Oh, he's no
ordinaryman.
He's rich.
When hiswifedied...
she left him with
a terrible heartache.
Andwhenyourhusband died...
he leftyou
with a terriblefortune.
Oh, Max,you reallyarea beast.
You and Georg are
likefamilyto me.
That'swhyl wanttosee
you twoget married.
We must keepall that lovely
moneyin thefamily.
Whatareyou doing there?
CaptainVonTrapp!
I wasjust looking for--
I didn'tsee--
I mean, I didn't knowyouwere--
Heil Hitler!
Whoareyou?
I havea telegram
for Herr Detweiler.
I'm Herr Detweiler.
Yes, sir.
All right,you'vedelivered
yourtelegram. Nowgetout.
Oh, Georg, he'sjusta boy.
Yes, and I'mjustanAustrian.
What's gonna happen's
going to happen.
Just makesure
itdoesn't happen toyou.
Max, don'tyou ever
saythatagain!
You know I have
no political convictions.
Can I help it
ifotherpeopledo?
Oh,yes,you can help it!
You must help it.
Hello.
You'refaraway.
Whereareyou?
In aworld that's disappearing,
I'm afraid.
- ChildrenChattering']
- Is thereanywayl could bringyou back...
totheworld I'm in?
Chattering, Screaming
Sew, a needle pulling thread
♪♪La, anotetofollowsew♪♪
Tea, a drinkwithjam and bread
Thatwill bring us backto Do
Oh, oh, oh
Doe, a deer
♪♪A femaledeer♪♪
- Father!
Oh, Captain.
You're home.
Comeoutofthatwateratonce!
Oh.You must be
Baroness Schraeder.
Oh, I'm soaked
totheskin!
BlowsWhistle
Straight line!
This is Baroness Schraeder.
Andthese:.
Are mychildren.
Howdoyou do?
All right, go inside.
Dryoff. Clean up.
Changeyourclothes.
Report backhere.
Immediately!
Fraulein,youwill
stayhere, please.
I, uh, ahem...
thinkl'd bettergo
seewhat Max is upto.
Now, Fraulein...
I wanta truthful
answerfromyou.
Yes, Captain?
Is it possible--
orcould I have
just imagined it--
Have mychildren,
byanychance...
been climbing trees today?
Yes, Captain.
I see.
Andwhere, mayl ask...
did theygetthese--
Playclothes.
Is thatwhatyou call them?
Imadethem:.
From thedrapes that used
to hang in mybedroom.
Drapes?
Theystill had
plentyofwearleft.
Thechildren have been
everywhere in them.
Doyou mean totell me
that mychildren...
have been roaming aboutSalzburg...
dressed up in nothing
butsomeold drapes?
Mm-hmm, and having
a marvelous time.
Theyhave uniforms.
Straitjackets,
ifyou'll forgive me.
I will notforgiveyou forthat.
Children cannotdoeverything
they'resupposed todo...
iftheyhavetoworryabout
theirprecious clothes.
Theyhaven'tcomplainedyet.
Well, theywouldn'tdare.
Theyloveyou too much.
Theyfearyou too much.
I don'twishyou todiscuss
mychildren in this manner.
You'vegotto hearfrom someone.
You're neverhome long enough--
I said I don'twantto
hearanymorefromyou...
- aboutmychildren.
- I knowyou don't, butyou'vegotto!
Now, take Liesl--
You'll notsayoneword
about Liesl, Fraulein.
You'regonnawake up
and find she's awoman.
Youwon'teven know her.
Friedrich, he's a boy,
but hewants to bea man likeyou...
and there's noone
toshow him how.
Don'tyou daretell me
about myson.
Brigitta could tellyou
about him...
ifyou'd let hergetclosetoyou.
She notices everything.
And Kurt pretends he's tough
nottoshow how hurt he is...
- Fraulein--
-whenyou brush him aside.
- Thatwill do.
- Thewayyou doall ofthem.
Louisa, I don't knowabout.
Isaidthatwilldo!!
And the littleones
justwantto be loved.
Oh, please, Captain,
lovethem, lovethem all.
I don'tcareto hear
anything furtherfromyou.
I am notfinishedyet, Captain!
Oh,yes,you are, Captain--
Fraulein.
Now,youwill pack
yourthings this minute...
andreturntotheabbey
♪♪ Thehillsarealive♪♪
♪♪ Withthesoundofmusic♪♪
What's that?
It's singing.
Yes, I realize it's singing...
butwho is singing?
Thechildren.
♪♪:.Forathousandyears♪♪
Thechildren?
I taughtthem something
tosing forthe baroness.
♪♪Myheartwantstosing'♪♪
♪♪Fverysong'♪♪
♪♪Ithears♪♪
♪♪Fverysong'thatithears♪♪
♪♪Myheartwantstobeat♪♪
Likethewings
ofthe birds that rise
From the laketothetrees
Tothetrees
♪♪Myheartwantstosigh♪♪
♪♪Likeachimethatfies♪♪
From a church on a breeze
♪♪ Tolaughlikeabrook♪♪
- Humming
-♪♪ Whenittripsandfalls♪♪
♪♪Cverstonesonits way♪♪
♪♪Cnits way♪♪
- SingingAlong
-♪♪ Tosing'throughthenight♪♪
♪♪Likealarkwho
islearning'topray♪♪
- I gotothe hills
- Children StopSinging
When myheart is lonely
♪♪Iknowlwillhear♪♪
♪♪ Whatl'veheardbefore♪♪
- Myheartwill be blessed
- Children Harmonizing
With thesound ofmusic
And I'll
With Children
Sing
Once
More
Laughs
Edelweiss.
Laughs Softly
You nevertold me
howenchantingyourchildren are.
Don'tgoaway.
Fraulein.
I...
behaved badly.
I apologize.
I'm fartoooutspoken.
It's oneofmyworstfaults.
Youwere right.
I don't know mychildren.
There's still time, Captain.
Theywantso much to beclosetoyou.
You brought music
backintothe house.
I'd forgotten.
Fraulein.
I wantyou tostay.
I askyou tostay.
Ifl could beofanyhelp--
You havealready.
Morethanyou know.
Marta...curtain!
Maria High on a hill was
a lonelygoatherd
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl lay-ee-o
Loudwas thevoice
ofthe lonelygoatherd
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl-o
Folks in a town that
was quite remote heard
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl lay-ee-o
Lustyand clear
From thegoatherd's throat heard
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl-o
Children
O-ho laydee-o-dl-ee-o
O-ho Laydee-o-dl-ay
O-ho Laydee-o-dl-ee-o
Laydee-o-dl-eeO-lay
Marta!
Gretl, the prince!
Maria A princeon the bridge
ofa castle moat heard
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl lay-ee-o
Children Men on a roadwith
a load totote heard
Layee-o-dl Layeeo-dl-oo
Men in the midst
ofa tabled'hote heard
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl lay-ee-o
Men drinking beer
with a foam afloat heard
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl-oo
Maria]♪♪Cnelittlegirlin
apalepinkcoatheard♪♪
♪♪Layee-o-dlLayee-o-dllay-ee-o♪♪
Sheyodeled back
tothe lonelygoatherd
♪♪Layee-o-dlLayee-o-dl-oo♪♪
Maria]♪♪Soonhermama with
agleaming'gloatheard♪♪
♪♪Layee-o-dlLayee-o-dllay-ee-o♪♪
♪♪ Whataduetforagirlandgoatherd♪♪
♪♪Layee-o-dllayee-o-dl-oo♪♪
Mm-hmm-hmm-hmm
Ho-dl-ay-ee
O-dl-ay-ee-ee
O-dl-ay-ee
Oh-oh-oh-oh
Laydee-o-dl-ay-o
Laydee-o-dl-ee
Laydee-o-dl-ay
Oh-oh-oh-oh
Laydee-o-dl-ay-o
Laydee-o-dl-eeO-lay
One littlegirl in
a pale pinkcoat heard
Laydee-o-dl
Laydee-o-dl-ay-woo-woo
Sheyodeled back
tothe lonelygoatherd
Laydee-o-dl Laydee-o-dl-oo
Soon hermamawith
a gleaming gloat heard
Laydee-o-dl
Laydee-o-dl-ay-mm-hmm
Whata duetfora girl and goatherd
Layee-o-dl Layee-o-dl-oo
Happyarethey
Laydee-o Laydee-lee-o
O-laydee-o Laydee-lay-dee-o
Soon theirduet
will becomea trio
Laydee-o-dl Laydee-o-dl-oo
O-dl-ay-ee
O-dl-ay-ee-ee
O-dl-ay-deeO-dl-ay
O-dl-ay-deeO-dl-ee
O-dl-lay-dee-o-dl
Lay-dee-o-dl-ay
- Whew!
- Laughing']
Bravo!
Verygood!
Wonderful.
Canwe reallykeep
the puppetshow, Uncle Max?
Ofcourseyou may, mydarlings.
Whyelsewould
I have had the bill...
senttoyourfather?
Canwe reallykeepthem?
Well done, Fraulein.
I reallyam very,
verymuch impressed.
They'reyourchildren, Captain.
Mydear, is there
anythingyou can'tdo?
Well, I'm notsure
I'll makeaverygood nun.
Ifyou have problems,
I'd be happyto helpyou.
Attention!
Attention, everyone.
I havean announcementto make.
Surprise, surprise.
Today, aftera long
and desperatesearch...
I havefinallyfound
a mostexciting entry...
fortheSalzburg folkfestival.
Congratulations, Max.
Whowillyou be
exploiting this time?
Ha-ha!
TheSaint Ignatius choir?
Guess again.
Uh.. let mesee...
the Kloppman choir?
No, no, no.
- No, no?
- No, no.
Tell us.
Asinging group
all in onefamily.
You'll neverguess, Georg.
Whata charming idea.
Uh,whosefamily?
Yours.
They'll bethetalk
ofthefestival.
What's sofunny?
You are, Max.
You'reexpensive...
butveryfunny.
Butyou heard them.
They'll bea sensation!
No, Max.
It's awonderful idea.
Fresh, original.
Max, mychildren
do notsing in public.
Well,you can't blame me
fortrying.
Children,whoshall
we hearfrom next?
Who?
Yes.
ClearsThroat
Thevote is unanimous.
You, Captain.
Me?
I don't understand.
Please.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
I'm told that
a long timeago...
youwerequitegood.
Well, thatwas avery,
very,verylong timeago.
I remember, Father.
- Playus somethingwe know.
- Please.
Well...
Whydidn'tyou tell me?
What?
To bring along myharmonica.
Edelweiss
Everymorning
You greet me
Small andwhite
Clean and bright
You lookhappy
♪♪ Tomeetme♪♪
♪♪Blossomofsnow♪♪
♪♪Mayyoubloomandgrow♪♪
Bloom and grow
Forever
Edelweiss
Bless myhomeland
Forever
Edelweiss
Together
Everymorning
You greet me
Small andwhite
Clean and bright
Together
You lookhappy
To meet me
Blossom ofsnow
Mayyou bloom and grow
Bloom and grow
Forever
Edelweiss
Bless myhomeland
Forever
Anytimeyou saytheword, Georg...
you can be partofmynewact--
- Chuckles
- TheVonTrapp FamilySingers.
I haveawonderful idea, Georg.
Let's reallyfill
this housewith music.
You mustgivea grand
and glorious partyforme...
while I'm here.
A party?
ChildrenTogether
Please, Father! Please!
I thinkit's high time
I metallyourfriends...
here in Salzburg
and theymet me.
Don'tyou agree?
I seewhatyou mean.
Children
Oh, please, Father!
Children, it's timetogoto bed.
Come, now, saygood night.
Good night, Father.
Good night.
Good night, Baroness.
Good night, Father.
Good night.
It'll be myfirst party, Father!
Hello, HerrZeller.
Baroness Schraeder.
Good evening, HerrZeller.
Baroness.
Howdoyou do?
Good evening.
I supposeyou noticed
theobvious display...
oftheAustrian flag
in the hallway?
Thewomen lookso beautiful.
I thinktheylookugly.
Youjustsaythat
becauseyou'rescared ofthem.
Silly, onlygrown-up men
arescared ofwomen.
I thinkthe men lookbeautiful.
Howwouldyou know?
Liesl,whoareyou dancingwith?
Nobody.
Oh,yes,you are.
Mayl havethis dance?
I'd bedelighted,young man.
Whydidn'tyou children
tell meyou could dance?
Wewereafraidyou'd
make us dancetogether.
TheVonTrapp Family Dancers.
What's thatthey're playing?
It's the Laendler.
It's anAustrian folkdance.
Show me.
Oh, Kurt, I haven'tdanced that
since I was a littlegirl.
Oh,you remember. Please?
- Well...
- Please.
All right.
Comeon overhere.
Nowyou bow, and I curtsy.
Likethis?
Fine. Nowwegofor
a littlewalk.Thisway.
1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3...
I, 2, 3,
steptogether
Now, step, hop.
Step, hop.
Now, turn under.
Notquite.
Thisway.
Hop,step, hop:.
And under--
Kurt,we'll haveto practice.
Um, doallow me,willyou?
Mm-hmm.
I don't rememberanymore.
Yourface is all red.
Is it?
I don'tsuppose
I'm used todancing.
Applause]
Thatwas beautifullydone.
Whata lovelycoupleyou make.
Yes. It's timethechildren
said good night.
Yes,we'll be in the hall
in a moment.
We'vegotsomething
veryspecial prepared.
- Right?
- Right.
Comeon!
All that needless
worrying, Georg.
You thoughtyouwouldn't
find a friend atthe party.
A bitchillyout
tonight, isn't it?
Oh, I don't know.
Itseemed ratherwarm to me.
WhistlingThroughTeeth
Ladies and gentlemen...
thechildren
ofCaptainVonTrapp...
wish tosay
good nighttoyou.
There's a sad sortofclanging
From theclockin the hall
And the bells in thesteeple, too
And up in the nursery,
an absurd little bird
Is popping outtosaycuckoo
Cuckoo, cuckoo
♪♪Regretfullytheytellus♪♪
Butfirmlytheycompel us
Tosaygood-bye
Cuckoo
Toyou
So long, farewell
Aufwiedersehen, Good night
I hatetogo
And leavethis prettysight
So long, farewell
Aufwiedersehen,Adieu
Adieu, adieu
Toyou andyou andyou
So long, farewell
Au revoir,Aufwiedersehen
I'd liketostay
And taste myfirstchampagne
Yes?
No.
♪♪Solong, farewell♪♪
Aufwiedersehen, Good-bye
I leaveand heave
Asigh and saygood-bye
Good-bye
I'm glad
Togo
I cannottell a lie
I flit
I float
I fleetlyflee
I fly
Thesun
Has gone
To bed
And so must I
♪♪Solong'♪♪
♪♪Farewell♪♪
Aufwiedersehen
Good-bye
They'reextraordinary.
Whattheywould do
atthefestival!
Oh,young lady, I must
havewordswithyou.
Georg,you're notgoing
to letthis girl getaway.
She has tojoin the party.
No, really, I--
Shh. Stop it.
Georg, please.
You can ifyouwantto, Fraulein.
I insist.Youwill be mydinnerpartner.
This is business.
Franz, setanotherplace
nextto minefor Fraulein Maria.
Why...whateveryou say,
Herr Detweiler.
Well, itappears
to beall arranged.
Itcertainlydoes.
I'm notsuitablydressed.
Uh,well,you can change.
We'll waitforyou.
Captain,you must be
veryproud ofyouryoungsters.
I am.Thankyou, Baroness.
Is therea more
beautiful expression...
ofwhat is good
in this countryofours...
than the innocentvoices
ofourchildren?
Oh, come, now, Baron,
wouldyou have us believe...
thatAustria alone holds
a monopolyonvirtue?
HerrZeller, someofus prefer...
Austrianvoices raised in song...
to uglyGerman threats.
Theostrich buries
his head in thesand...
and sometimes... in theflag.
Perhaps those
whowouldwarnyou...
thattheAnschluss is coming--
Anditiscoming, Captain--
Perhapstheywould
getfurtherwithyou:.
Bysetting
theirwords to music.
Ifthe Nazis takeoverAustria...
I have nodoubtthatyouwill
betheentiretrumpetsection.
You flatterme, Captain.
Oh, howclumsyofme.
I meanttoaccuseyou.
It'sverykind ofyou to
offerto help me, Baroness.
I'm delighted, Maria.
I reallydon'tthink
I do haveanything...
thatwould be
appropriate.
Now,where is that
lovelylittlething...
youwerewearing
theotherevening...
when thecaptain couldn't
keep his eyes offyou?
Couldn't keep his eyes offme?
Come, mydear,
wearewomen.
Let's not pretendwedon't know
when a man notices us.
Hereweare.
Thecaptain notices
everybodyand everything.
There's no need tofeel
sodefensive, Maria.
You arequiteattractive,
you know.
Thecaptainwould
hardlybea man...
ifhedidn't noticeyou.
Baroness, I hopeyou'rejoking.
Notatall.
But I've never
donea thing to--
Butyou don't haveto, mydear.
There's nothing more
irresistibletoa man...
than awoman
who's in lovewith him.
In lovewith him?
Ofcourse.
Butwhat makes itso nice...
is hethinks he's in lovewithyou.
Butthat's nottrue.
Surelyyou've noticed theway
he looks intoyoureyes.
And,you know, uh...
you blushed in his arms
whenyouweredancingjust now.
Don'ttakeittoheart.
He'll getoveritsoon enough,
I should think.
Men do,you know.
Then I should go.
Imustn'tstayhere.
Is theresomething
I can doto help?
No, nothing.
Yes.
Pleasedon'tsayaword
aboutthis tothecaptain.
No. No, I wouldn'tdream ofit.
Cood-bye, Maria.
I'm sureyou'll make
averyfine nun.
Champagne, darling.
I feel likecelebrating.
Cheers.
You knowsomething?
Perhaps.
Then ifyou'resoclever...
tell me howtoget
ourlittle Fraulein...
to use herinfluence
with Georg.
I wantthosechildren
in thefestival.
Elsa, this is important
toAustria.
Itwouldn'tdoyou
anyharm, either.
I'vethoughtofthat.
Well, ifit's
a matterofinfluence...
maybetheoneyou have
to betalking to is me.
- Two.
- Three.
Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Seven.
- Eight.
- Grunts
- Four.
- Two.
- Seven.
- Five.
- Two!
- Six.
- Groans
Nervous Chuckle
Isn'tthis fun?
Um--
Four.
I'm numberfive.
Oh,yes.
Eight.
Two.
Four
- Six!
- Ohh!
Two.
Baroness Schraeder,
doyou mind ifwestop now?
We'retired.
Oh,whateveryouwant, dear.
We'll do itagain tomorrow.
Thecountry's so restful, isn't it?
Havesome lemonade.
Oh, there must be
an easierway.
I geta fiendish delight...
thinking ofyou
as the motherofseven.
Howdoyouplantodoit?
Darling, haven'tyou everheard...
ofa delightful littlething
called boarding school?
Baroness Machiavelli.
Mm-hmm.
Uncle Max,where's Father?
I thinkhe's in the house.
What's the matter
with allyou gloomypusses?
Nothing.
I knowwhatwe'll do.
Let's havea rehearsal.
Whatfor?
Let's make believewe'restanding
on thestageatthefestival.
I don'tfeel likesinging.
Notwithout Fraulein Maria.
Liesl, gettheguitar.
Comeon, Marta.
Everybodyintothegroup.
You knowyourplaces.
Get inyourplaces.
That's right.
Becheerful.
Give us the key, Liesl.
Now, impress me.
Ah
- Ah
Friedrich, Gretl,
whydon'tyou sing?
I can't. I'vegota sorefinger.
Butyou sang so beautifully
the nightofthe party.
Comeon, all ofyou.
Trysomethingyou know.
Enjoyit. Becheerful.
All right, Liesl.
The hills arealive
With thesound ofmusic
♪♪Ahahahah♪♪
♪♪ Withsongstheyhavesung'♪♪
Fora thousandyears
♪♪Ahahahah♪♪
The hills fill myheart
Ah ah ah ah
With thesound ofmusic
♪♪Ahahahah:.♪♪
Theyjustwanted
tosing forme...
bless theirhearts.
That's lovely, lovely.
Don'tstop.
Hmm?
Uh, something long
and cool, Georg?
No, thankyou, darling.
Father?
Yes, Brigitta?
Is ittrue Fraulein Maria
isn'tcoming back?
Fraulein Maria?Yes,
I suppose it's true.
What have wegot here?
Pinklemonade.
Lacedwith:. lemonade.
Ooh.
I don't believe it, Father.
Hmm? Don't believewhat, darling?
About Fraulein Maria.
Oh, Fraulein Maria!
Didn't I tellyou
what hernotesaid?
Oh, I'm sure I did.
Shesaid she missed her
lifeattheabbeytoo much.
Shehadtoleaveus.
And that's all there is to it.
I thinkl'm braveenough
totrysomeofthat.
Shedidn'teven
saygood-bye.
Shedid in hernote.
Thatisn'tthesamething.
Nottoosweet, nottoosour.
Justtoo, uh... pink.
Father, whoisournew
governessgoing'tobe?
Well...
you're notgoing to have
a governess anymore.
All
We're not?
No.
You'regoing to have
a new mother.
A new mother?
Wetalkedaboutitlastnight.
It's all settled...
andwe'reall going
to beveryhappy.
Hmm?
Well, all right,
all right, all right.
Now, run offand play.
Ring Ring
Yes, mychildren?
Uh, myname is Liesl.
Yes, Liesl.
We-- mybrothers
and sisters--
Wewanttosee
Fraulein Maria.
Fraulein Maria?
Oh, Maria!
Come in, please.
Wait here.
I'm Sister Margaretta.
I understandyou've been
inquiring about Maria.
We havetosee her.
Willyou tell herwe're here, please?
I'm afraid I can'tdothat.
Oh, butyou'vegotto.
We havetosee her.
- She's ourgoverness.
- Wewant herback!
- Shedidn'tevensaygood-bye.
- It's veryimportant.
All wewanttodo
is talkto her.
I'm verysorry, children,
but Maria is in seclusion.
She hasn't been seeing anyone.
She'll see us.
I knowshewill.
I wanttoshow hermyfinger.
Oh, someothertime, dear.
I'll tell herthatyouwere here.
Itwas sweetofyou tocall.
Please!
Run along, children.
Run along home.
Sister Margaretta!
- Please!
Good-bye, children.
Whatwas thatabout,
Sister Margaretta?
TheVonTrappchildren,
Reverend Mother.
Theywanttosee Maria.
Has shespokenyet?
Has shetoldyou anything?
Shedoesn'tsayaword,
Reverend Mother.
Except in prayer.
Poorchild.
It's strange.
Sheseems happy
to be backhere...
andyet... andyet
she's unhappy, too.
Perhaps I have beenwrong...
in leaving heraloneso long.
I thinkyou'd better
bring herto me...
even ifshe's notyet ready.
Yes, Reverend Mother.
SisterAugusta...
takeournew postulant
tothe robing room.
God blessyou, mydaughter.
KnockOn Door
Ave!!
Yes, bring herin.
You've been unhappy.
I'm sorry.
Reverend Mother.
Whydid theysendyou
backto us?
Theydidn'tsend me back,
Mother. I left.
Sitdown, Maria.
Tell mewhat happened.
Well, I...
I was frightened.
Frightened?
Weretheyunkind toyou?
Oh, no.
No, I was-- I was confused.
I--I felt...
I've neverfelt
thatwaybefore.
I couldn'tstay.
I knewthat here I'd be
awayfrom it. I'd besafe.
Maria, ourabbeyis not
to be used as an escape.
What is ityou can'tface?
I can'tface him again.
Him?
Thankyou,
Sister Margaretta.
CaptainVonTrapp?
Areyou in lovewith him?
I don't know!
I don't know, I...
The baroness said I was.
She... shesaid that
hewas in lovewith me...
but I didn'twant
to believe it.
Oh, thereweretimeswhen
wewould lookateach other--
Oh, Mother, I could hardlybreathe.
Didyou let him see
howyou felt?
Ifl did, I didn't know it.
That'swhat's been torturing me.
I was there
on Cod's errand.
To haveasked forhis love
would have beenwrong.
I couldn'tstay.
Ijustcouldn't!
I'm readyatthis moment
totake myvows.
Please help me.
Maria...
the loveofa man and
awoman is holy, too.
You havea great
capacityto love.
Whatyou mustfind out...
is howGodwantsyou
tospendyourlove.
But I've pledged
mylifetoGod.
I've pledged mylife
to his service.
Mydaughter,
ifyou lovethis man...
itdoesn't mean
you loveGod less.
No.
You mustfind out.
You mustgo back.
Oh, Mother,you can't
askmetodothat.
Please let mestay.
I beg ofyou.
Maria, thesewalls
were not built...
toshutout problems.
You havetofacethem.
You haveto livethe life
youwere born to live.
Climbeverymountain
♪♪Searchhighandlow♪♪
Followeverybyway
Everypathyou know
Climbeverymountain
Ford everystream
Followeveryrainbow
Tillyou findyourdream
♪♪A dreamthatwillneed♪♪
♪♪Alltheloveyoucangive♪♪
Everydayofyourlife
Foras long asyou live
Climbeverymountain
Ford everystream
Followeveryrainbow
Tillyou findyourdream
Adream thatwill need
All the loveyou can give
Everydayofyourlife
Foras long asyou live
Climbeverymountain
Ford everystream
♪♪Followeveryrainbow♪♪
Tillyou findyourdream
Now, it's not like
mychildren...
to besecretive.
We're not being
secretive, Father.
Mm-hmm.And it's not
like mychildren...
to be latefordinner.
We losttrack
ofthetime.
- Yes!
Nowwho's going to bethefirstone
totell methetruth?
Friedrich?
Brigitta? Liesl?
Wheredoyou think
wewere, Father?
Hmm? Now--
Well, ifyou don't believe us...
you must havesome idea
whereyou thinkwewere.
Giggling
- Aha! Marta!
- Yes, Father
You tell me.
Friedrich toldyou, Father.
Wewere berrypicking.
I forgot.Youwere
berrypicking!
- Yeah!
All afternoon?
We picked thousands ofthem.
Thousands?
I gotthe most.
What kind ofberries?
Uh, blueberries, sir.
Blueberries!
Mmm!
Yes!Yes, ofcourse!
It's, uh, tooearly
forblueberries.
Theywerestrawberries.
Strawberries?
It's been socold lately,
theyturned blue.
Aw!Tsk!!Tsk!!
Tsk!!Tsk!!Tsk!!
Verywell.
Show methe berries.
Um,well...
Show methe berries
you picked. Comeon.
Wedon't havethem anymore.
You don't havethem anymore?
Well,what happened tothem?
We--we...
Weatethem!
You atethem?
Yes!
Theyweredelicious!
Verywell.
Sinceyou'veobviously
stuffedyourselves...
full ofthousands
ofdelicious berries...
youcan'tbehungryanymore:.
So I'lljust haveto
simplytell frau Schmidt...
to, uh, skipyourdinner.
It's allyourfault!
Weshould have
told him thetruth.
And made him
boiling mad at us?
It's betterthan
starving todeath.
Wedidn'tdo
anythingwrong.
Wejustwanted tosee her.
Mystomach's making noises.
The leastthey
could havedone...
was to let us sayhello.
I wonderwhat
grass tastes like.
I feel awful.
When Fraulein Maria
wanted tofeel better...
she used tosing
thatsong, remember?
Let's tryit.
Raindrops on roses
Andwhiskers on kittens
Brightcopperkettles
Andwarm woolen mittens
Brown paperpackages
Tied upwith strings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
Whydon't I feel better?
Girls inwhitedresses
With bluesatin sashes
Maria'sVoiceJoins Snowflakes
thatstayon mynoseand eyelashes
- Silverwhitewinters
- ChildrenShouting']
That melt intosprings
Thesearea few
ofmyfavoritethings
When thedog bites
When the beestings
When I'm feeling sad
I simplyremember
myfavoritethings
And then I don'tfeel
So bad
Oh, children,
I'm soglad toseeyou!
We missedyou!
Oh, I missedyou.
Kurt, howareyou?
Hungry.
Gretl,what happened
toyourfinger?
Itgotcaught.
Caught inwhat?
Friedrich's teeth.
Liesl,
you all right?
Justfair.
Manytelegrams been
delivered here lately?
Noneatall, Fraulein,
but I'm learning toaccept it.
I'll beglad
when school begins.
Oh, Liesl...
you can't useschool
toescapeyourproblems.
You havetofacethem.
Oh, I haveso much
totellyou all.
We havethings
totellyou, too.
I'm sureyou do.
The most importantthing...
is that Fatheris
going to be married.
Married?
Yes, to Baroness
Schraeder.
Oh, I see.
Ch, Father, look!!
Fraulein Maria's
come backfrom theabbey!
Good evening, Captain.
Good evening.
All right, everyone inside.
Goand getyourdinner.
Dinner!
You leftwithout
saying good-bye...
even tothechildren.
Well, itwaswrong ofme.
Forgive me.
Whydidyou?
Pleasedon'taskme.
Anyway, the reason
no longerexists.
FrauleinMaria.
You'vereturned
Isn't itwonderful, Georg?
Mayl wishyou
everyhappiness, Baroness...
andyou, too, Captain.
Thechildren tell me
you'reto be married.
Thankyou, mydear.
You are back
to, uh, stay?
Onlyuntil arrangements...
can be madefor
anothergoverness.
Thereyouare!!
I reallymustspeaktocook...
aboutthewienerschnitzel.
It is entirelytoodelicious
formyfigure.
And it makesyou
much tooquiet...
atthedinnertable...
orwas itthewine?
Oh, undoubtedlythewine.
You have no ideawhat kind
oftrouble I'm having...
trying todecide
whattogiveyou...
forawedding present.
Oh, I know, I'm enough...
but I dowantyou to have...
some littletrifle
fortheoccasion.
Atfirst, I thought
ofa fountain pen...
butyou'vealreadygotone.
And then I thought perhaps
avilla in thesouth ofFrance...
buttheyareso difficult
togiftwrap.
Georg, howdoyou feel
aboutyachts?
A long, sleekone
forthe Mediterranean...
ora tinyone
foryourbathtub, hmm?
Elsa.
Andwheretogo
on ourhoneymoon?
Now, that is a real problem.
I thoughta triparound
theworldwould be lovely.
Then I said, "Oh, Elsa...
there must besomeplace
bettertogo."
Don'tworry, darling. I--
Elsa.
Yes, Georg?
It's no use...
youandl.
I've been dishonest
to both ofus...
and utterly
unfairtoyou.
When two people
talkofmarriage--
No, don't.
Don'tsayanotherword,
Georg, please.
You see, um...
thereareotherthings
I've been thinking of.
Fond as I am ofyou...
I reallydon'tthink
you'rethe right man forme.
You're, um...
you're much too independent.
And I--I need someone
who needs medesperately...
orat least needs
mymoneydesperately.
I'veenjoyed everymoment
we've had together.
I dothankyou forthat.
Now, if, um, ifyou'll forgive me...
I'll go inside, packmylittle bags...
and return toVienna,
where I belong.
And somewhereoutthere
is ayoung lady...
who I think...
will neverbea nun.
Aufwiedersehen, darling.
Hello.
I thought Ijust might
findyou here.
Was theresomething
youwanted?
Hmm?
No, no, no.
Sitdown. Please.
Please.
Uh, mayl?
You know, I was...
I was thinking...
and I waswondering
twothings.
Whydidyou
run awaytotheabbey?
And...
whatwas it
that madeyou come back?
Well, I...
had an obligation tofulfill...
and I...
I came back
tofulfill it.
Is thatall?
And I missed
thechildren.
Yes.
Onlythechildren?
No.Yes!
Isn't it right I should
have missed them?
Oh,yes!
Yes, ofcourse!
I was onlyhoping
that perhapsyou...
perhapsyou might, uh...
Yes?
Well, uh...
nothingwas thesame
whenyouwereawayand...
it'll beall wrong again
afteryou leave.
And Ijustthought
perhapsyou might, uh...
changeyourmind?
I'm surethe baroness...
will beableto make
things fineforyou.
Maria...
there isn'tgoing
to beanybaroness.
There isn't?
No.
I don't understand.
Well,we've, um, called off
ourengagement,you see, and...
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Yes.
- You are?
- Mm-hmm.
- You did?
- Yes.
Well,you can't marry
someonewhenyou're...
in lovewith
someoneelse.
Canyou?
The Reverend Mother
always says...
"when the Lord
closes a door...
somewhere
heopens awindow."
Whatelsedoes the
Reverend Mothersay?
Thatyou haveto look
foryourlife.
Is thatwhy
you came back?
And haveyou
found it...
Maria?
I thinkl have.
I know I have.
I loveyou.
Oh, can this
be happening to me?
Perhaps I had awicked childhood
Perhaps I had a miserableyouth
Butsomewhere in mywicked,
miserable past
There must have been
a momentoftruth
Forhereyou are
Standing there
Loving me
Whetherornot
You should
Sosomewhere in myyouth
Orchildhood
I must havedonesomething good
Nothing comes from nothing
Nothing evercould
Sosomewhere in myyouth
Orchildhood
I must havedone
Something
Good
Doyou knowwhen I first
started lovingyou?
That night
atthedinnertable...
whenyou saton that
ridiculous pinecone.
Laughing
What?
Laughs
I knewthefirsttime
you blewthatsillywhistle.
Oh, mylove.
Forhereyou are
Standing there
Loving me
Whetherornot
You should
Sosomewhere in myyouth
Orchildhood
I must havedone
Something
Good
Nothing comes from nothing
Nothing evercould
Sosomewhere in myyouth
Orchildhood
I must havedone
Something
Good
Maria.
Is thereanyone
I should goto...
toaskpermission
to marryyou?
Well,whydon't
weask...
-thechildren?
- Thechildren?
-Thechildren?
Church Bells Ringing
Organ Plays
Howdoyou solve
a problem like Maria?
Howdoyou catch
a cloud and pin itdown?
Howdoyou find aword
that means Maria?
Aflibbertigibbet,
Awill-o'-thewisp
Aclown
Manya thingyou know
you'd liketotell her
Manya thing
sheoughtto understand
But howdoyou make herstay
And listen toallyou say?
Howdoyou keep
awave upon thesand?
Oh, howdoyou solve
a problem like Maria?
Howdoyou hold
a moonbeam inyourhand?
Church Bells Ring
MusicPlaying']
Herr Detweiler!
Heil Hitler.
Oh. Good afternoon,
HerrZeller.
Perhapsyou've not heard.
I'm nowthegauleiter
Heil Hitler.
Uh... heil Hitler.
I havejustcomefrom the house
ofCaptainVonTrapp...
incidentally, theonlyone
in the neighborhood...
notflying theflag
oftheThird Reich...
sincetheAnschluss.
Butwe havedealt
with thatsituation.
Yourhousekeepertold me
that I would findyou here.
Itwas theonlyinformation
thewomanwould give me.
What kind ofinformation
areyou looking for?
Wewantto knowwhen
thecaptainwill be returning.
Well, he's on his honeymoon trip.
Uh, he's not been
in touchwith us.
Areyou asking meto believe
thatthecaptain...
has notcommunicatedwith
his children in overa month?
HerrZeller,
how manymen doyou know...
whocommunicate
with theirchildren...
whileon theirhoneymoon?
When hedoes return,
hewill beexpected tofill...
his properposition
in the neworder.
Naturally naturally
And mayl congratulateyou--
That is,yourpeople--
On deciding toallowthefestival...
togoon tonightas planned?
Whyshould it notgoon?
Nothing inAustria has changed.
Singing and music
will showthis totheworld.
Austria is thesame.
Heil Hitler.
Comeon, children,
let's go home.
Whywas hesocross?
Everybody's cross
thesedays, darling.
Maybetheflagwith
the blackspideron it...
makes people nervous.
Is Fathergoing to be in trouble?
Hedoesn't haveto be.
Thething todothesedays...
is togetalongwith everybody.
I wantyou all
to rememberthat...
tonightattheconcert.
Arewe reallygoing tosing...
beforeawhole lot
ofpeopletonight?
Ofcourse.
Look, theVonTrapp
FamilySingers.
And hereareyournames--
Liesl, Friedrich, Louisa, Brigitta...
Kurt, Marta, and Gretl.
Whyam I always last?
Becauseyou are
the most important.
Oh!
Therewego.
Uncle Max,
areyou sure Father...
will approveof
oursinging in public?
Oh, he'll be pleased
and proud.
Liesl, doyou thinkso?
Don'tyou trust me?
No!
You'reaveryintelligentgirl.
Laughs
Liesl! Liesl!
Rolfe!!
Rolfe, I'm so glad toseeyou.
It's been such--
Good afternoon.
Youwill takethis, please,
and deliverittoyourfather...
as soon as hecomes home.
He's on his honeymoon.
- I knowthat.
- You do?
We make itourbusiness to know
everything abouteveryone.
Who'swe?
Seethat hegets it.
What is it?
It's a telegram from Berlin.
Don'tyouwant
tocomeovertonight...
and deliverityourself?
I am nowoccupiedwith
more important matters...
andyourfatherbetterbe, too,
ifhe knowswhat's good forhim.
But, Rolfe--
ChildrenShouting']
Father!Father!
- Wedidn'texpectyou sosoon.
- Hello, hello, hello!
When didyou get back?
Didyou bring us
anysouvenirs from Paris?
Hello!!
Howareyou?
Whydidn'tyou
telephone us?
Wetriedto, butwe
couldn'tgetthrough.
I had nothing
todowith that, Georg.
Wecame back
as fastaswecould.
Well,well,well,
we missedyou!
We missed kissingyou
good night.
We missed all the noise
you make in the morning...
telling each other
to bequiet.
Mostly,we missed
hearingyou sing.
Oh,you came back
just in time.
Look, Fraulein Maria--
I mean, Mother.
We'regoing'tosing'
inthefestivaltonight.
What?
Yes,we've been rehearsing all--
Surprise! Surprise!
All right, surprises
foryou on theterrace.
Presents!
We'll talkabout
this inside.
I would havetoldyou,
butyouwereaway.
I had to make
a last-minutedecision.
I was fortunate
toenterthem atall.
Max.
They'll bethetalk
ofthefestival.
Imagine, seven children
in onefamily.
Max! Somehow I recall...
having made it
quitecleartoyou...
how I feel about
myfamilysinging in public.
Butthecommittee heard them.
Theywereenchanted.
Oh, Max,whatdid theysay?
I have neverheard
such enthusiasm.
Oh, darling, don'tyou think--
justthis once?
Absolutely
outofthequestion.
Georg, this is forAustria.
ForAustria?
There is noAustria!
ButtheAnschluss
happened peacefully.
Let's at least
begrateful forthat.
Grateful!
You know, Max...
sometimes I don't
believe I knowyou.
Father, I forgot.
This is foryou.
DoorShuts]
Maria, he has got
toat leastpretend:
toworkwith these people.
You mustconvince him.
Max, I can'taskhim
to be less than he is.
Then I'll talkto him.
Ifthechildren don'tsing
atthefestival...
well, itwill be
a reflection onAustria.
Oh, I know. Itwouldn't
do meanygood, either.
- Mother?
- Hmm?
Thatsounds so nice.
I likecallingyou mother.
I like hearing it.
You love Fatherverymuch.
I can tellyou do.
Verymuch.
Mother,whatdoyou dowhenyou
thinkyou lovesomeone--
I mean,whenyou stop
loving someone...
orhestops lovingyou?
Well,you crya little.
And thenyouwait
forthesun tocomeout.
Italways does.
There's so manythings
I thinkl should know...
but I don't.
I reallydon't.
Howcanyou?
Sometimes I feel theworld
is coming toan end.
And thenyou feel
it'sjust beginning?
Yes.
Itwas thatway
with me, Liesl.
And foryou, itwill be
justaswonderful, I promise.
Doyou reallythinkso?
Whenyou're 1 6
Going on 17
Waiting forlifetostart
♪♪Somebodykind♪♪
♪♪ Whotouchesyourmind♪♪
♪♪ Willsuddenlytouchyourheart♪♪
When that happens
Afterit happens
Nothing is quitethesame
Somehow I know
I'lljump upand go
Ifeverhecalls myname
Goneareyourold ideas oflife
Theold ideas growdim
Loand behold
You'resomeone'swife
Andyou belong to him
You maythink
this kind ofadventure
Nevermaycometoyou
Darling 1 6 going on 17
Waitayearortwo
I'll waitayear
Justwaitayear
Or
Two
Liesl
What is it?
Berlin.
They'veoffered me
a commission in theirnavy.
I've been requested
toaccept immediately...
and reporttotheirnaval base
at Bremerhaven tomorrow.
I knewsomething
likethiswould happen...
but I didn'tthink
itwould besosoon.
To refusethem would be
fatal forall ofus...
andjoining them
would be... unthinkable.
Getthechildren
all together.
Don'tsayanything that's
going to makethem worry.
Justgetthem ready.
We'vegottogetout
ofAustria...
and this house...
tonight.
Itstrains myback,
it breaks myheart...
when I thinkof
a certain singing group...
thatwill notappear
atthefestival tonight.
Bythetimeyou've
madetheannouncement...
we'll beoverthe border.
I hopeyou appreciate
thesacrifice I'm making.
You have nochoice.
I know.That'swhy
I'm making it.
Whydoesn't Father
turn the motoron?
Because hedoesn'twant
anyoneto hearus!
Shh!
Whatwill frau Schmidt
and Franzsay...
when theydiscover
we'regone?
They'll beableto
answertruthfully.
Theydidn't knowanything
about it ifanyoneasks them.
Will we becoming
backhere?
Someday, Liesl.
I do hopesomeday.
Are Fatherand Uncle Max
going to push thecar...
all thewaytoSwitzerland?
Shh!
Somethingwrong
withyourcar, Captain?
Yes, as a matter
offact...
wecouldn't
get itstarted.
Kobb.
FixCaptainVonTrapp's car...
sothat itwill start.
Car EngineStarts
Excellent, Kobb.
I've notaskedyou...
whereyou andyour
familyaregoing.
Norhaveyou asked me
whyl'm here.
Well, apparently,
we're both suffering...
from a deplorable
lackofcuriosity.
Youweresenta telegram,
whichyou did notanswer...
from the navy
oftheThird Reich.
I was underthe impression,
HerrZeller...
thatthecontents oftelegrams
inAustria are private!
At leasttheAustria I know.
I have myorders.
And theyaretotakeyou personally
to Bremerhaven tonight...
whereyouwill acceptyourcommission.
I'm afraid that's...
going to be
quite impossible.
You see,we, uh...
all ofus--
Theentirefamilywill be...
singing in thefestival tonight.
Asamatteroffact:.
That's where
we weregoing'now
Couldn't possibly
letthem down now.
Ijust hope
we're nottoo late.
Yes.
Andyou askmeto believe
thatyou, CaptainVonTrapp...
aresinging
in a concert?
Believe me,
itwill bea performance...
beyond anything
even I'vedreamtof.
Likeyou,
HerrZeller...
I, too, am a man
ofhidden talents.
Yes, um...here.
Program.
Itsays hereonlythe names
ofthechildren.
Itsays theVonTrapp
FamilySingers...
and I'm the head
oftheVonTrappfamily...
am I not?
And these, um, travel clothes
thatyou'reall wearing?
Ourcostumes, naturally.
HerrZeller,
this nightairis notgood...
forthechildren'svoices.
Well, a slightdelay
in myorders...
will not beserious.
Therefore...
youwill sing.
Youwillall sing.:
butonlybecausethat's
the waylwantittobe.
Itwill demonstratethat nothing
inAustria has changed.
Andwhenyou
arefinishedsinging.:
you, CaptainVonTrapp,
will betaken to Bremerhaven.
Now, ifyouwill all
get intoyourcar...
wewill escort
theVonTrapp FamilySingers...
tothefestival.
Noescortwill be necessary,
HerrZeller.
Necessary?
Apleasure, Captain.
Afterall,wewould notwantyou...
toget lost in thecrowds...
wouldwe?
No.
Sew, a needle pulling thread
A needle pulling thread
La, a notetofollowsew
A notetofollowsew
Tea, a drinkwithjam and bread
Adrinkwithjam and bread
Jam and bread,
Withjam and bread
Teawithjam and bread
Jam and bread,Jam and bread
Teawithjam,Jam and bread
Jam and bread
- Withjam
- A-B-C
A-B-C
- Withjam
- Do Re Mi
Do Re Mi
Teawithjam and bread
Withjam and bread
Withjam Withjam
And bread
Applause
MyfellowAustrians...
I shall not be
seeingyou again...
perhaps foraverylong time.
I would liketosing foryou now...
a lovesong.
I knowyou share
this love.
I praythatyouwill
neverlet itdie.
Edelweiss
Everymorningyou greet me
Small andwhite
Clean and bright
You lookhappyto meet me
Blossom ofsnow
Mayyou bloom and grow
Bloom and growforever
Edelweiss
Bless myhomeland forever
Edel...
Small andwhite
Clean and bright
You lookhappyto meet me
Blossom ofsnow
Mayyou bloom and grow
Bloom and growforever
Edelweiss
Bless myhomeland forever
I thinkit'll work.
I shall miss all ofyou.
I shall miss the money
I could have madewithyou.
Thankyou, ladies and gentlemen,
thankyou.
Thefestival competition
has cometo its conclusion...
except, ofcourse,
wedon't knowyet...
whatthat
conclusionwill be.
Andwhilethejudgesare
arriving'attheirdecision:.
Ihavebeengivenpermission
toofferyouanencore.
Thiswill bethe lastopportunity...
theVonTrappswill have
ofsinging together...
fora long, long time.
Fvennow:
offcialsare waiting'
inthisauditorium:.
ToescortCaptain Von Trapp
tohisnewcommand:
in the naval forces
oftheThird Reich.
Murmuring
Andso, ladiesandgentlemen:.
ThefamilyVonTrappagain...
to bidyou farewell.
Applause]
There's a sad sortofclanging
From theclockin the hall
And the bells in thesteeple, too
And up in the nursery,
an absurd little bird
Is popping outtosaycuckoo
Cuckoo
Regretfullytheytell us
Butfirmlytheycompel us
Tosaygood-bye
Toyou
So long, farewell,
Aufwiedersehen, good night
We hatetogo
and miss this prettysight
So long, farewell,
Aufwiedersehen, adieu
Adieu, adieu,
Toyou andyou andyou
So long, farewell,
Aufwiedersehen, good-bye
Weflit,wefloat,
Wefleetlyflee,wefly
So long, farewell,
Aufwiedersehen, good-bye
Thesun has goneto bed,
and so must I
Good-bye
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have herethedecision...
ofourdistinguishedjudges.
Wewill startwith theaward
forthird prize.
Forthishonor,
thejudgeshavenamed:
thefirstsoloistofthechoir
ofSt.Agathe'schurch:.
In Murbach--
Fraulein Schweiger.
AudienceLaughs]
Second prizeto...
theToby ReiserQuintet.
Thefirst prize...
the highest honor
in all Austria...
totheVonTrapp
FamilySingers.
ThefamilyVonTrapp.
They'regone!
Horns Honking
Doorbell Rings
Comewith me.
Ring
Quickly! Quickly!
I havea placeyou can hide.
Slowly.
Ring
Open this gate!
Good evening.
Hurryup,woman.
Two men in there!
Sixofyou, fan out
and covertheyard.
You two, coverthecorridor.
Oh, Reverend Mother,
wedidn't realize...
we'd puttheabbeyin this danger.
No, Maria.
Itwas rightforyou
tocome here.
Wethoughtwe might borrow
yourcaretaker's car.
I'm afraid ourcar
will doyou nogood now.
I've been listening
tothewireless.
The borders havejust been closed.
All right, the borders areclosed.
Thenwe'll drive up intothe hills...
and gooverthose
mountains on foot.
Thechildren.
We'll helpthem.
They'll beall right.
Wecan do itwithout help, Father.
Maria.
Youwill not bealone.
Remember, "I will lift up
mineeyes untothe hills...
from whencecometh myhelp."
Yes, Mother.
I'm scared.
Me, too.
God bewithyou.
- Mother.
- Yes?
Would it help ifwesang
aboutourfavoritethings?
No, darling.
This is onetime
itwould not help.
You must beveryquiet.
Hold tightto me.
Rattling
Comeon.
Let's trythe roof.
Gasp
Rolfe, please.
No,wait!
Maria...
children...
it'syouwewant,
notthem.
Putthatdown.
Notanothermove!
Orl'll... I'll shoot!
You'reonlya boy.
You don't really
belong tothem.
Staywhereyou are!
Comeawaywith us...
before it's too late.
Notanotherstep.
I'll killyou!
You givethatto me, Rolfe.
Didyou hearme?
I'll killyou!
Rolfe...
You'll never
beoneofthem.
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant, they're here!
They're here, Lieutenant!
BlowsWhistle
Whistle Blowing
Engines Stall
Reverend Mother.
I havesinned.
I, too, Reverend Mother.
What is this sin,
mychildren?
Adream thatwill need
All the loveyou can give
Everydayofyourlife
Foras long asyou live
Climbeverymountain
Ford everystream
Followeveryrainbow
Till
You
Find
Your
Dream